JUAN FRANCISCO TABARES.



Bogotá - Colombia



+3242547009



iuanfranciscot@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/jftabares/

https://www.jufrapps.com

About

My name is Francisco Tabares experienced Software Engineer with strong proficiency in web APIs, and data pipelines. Autonomous researcher on the Computer Vision field for an ongoing advanced side project. Industries of Digital Advertising, Customer Experience and Entertainment.

EDUCATION:

SYSTEM ENGINEER · Universidad de Buenos Aires - Argentina 02.2002 - 12.2008

Level: Professional Graduated · Area of study: Computer Engineering / Systems

High School · Colegio Militar Simon Bolivar - Bogotá - Colombia. 11.2001

LANGUAGES:

Spanish: (Native).

English: (Secondary).

WORK EXPERIENCE:

FULL STACK DEVELOPER / - Smart think - México / U.S.A

06.2020 – Actual.

Hierarchy: Senior Developer · Sector: Programming.

Full stack Engineer working for Mobile technologies. As a Sr Software Engineer I'm in charge of creating and maintaining microservices in a high availability/real-time environment and streamed apps, processing massive amounts of data and feeding reactive Mobile applications as well as several others which consume those services; Also participating in the research of new technologies to improve company's Mobile experience.

Tech used Vue.JS / FIREBASE / NODE Js / WebRTC / Socket.IO

FULL STACK DEVELOPER / - JAYA - U.S.A / Colombia

01.2020 - 05.2020.

Hierarchy: Senior Developer · Sector: Programming.

I worked under high-quality waterfall-like development standards. Using Agile as the main day-to-day methodology; doing scrums, pair-programming, code reviews, code refactors, unit testing, BDD, and all of this over a Continuous Integration process. It's been one of the most interesting projects where multiple big teams co-worked together to build a giant solution.

Tech used REACT / JAVASCRIPT / FIREBASE / NODE Js / VueJS / GraphQL / ANGULAR / MongoDB

FULL STACK DEVELOPER / - EasyAppDev - U.S.A

04.2018 - 01.2020.

Hierarchy: Management / Management · Sector: Programming · Industry: Selling Apps.

I worked making web based applications in different architectures, for clients such as Nike, Johnson & Johnson, AARP, HunterDouglas among others. I used several technologies such as ZF2, Drupal, NodeJS, Backbone, Ant, MongoDB, and MySQL as well as MERN stack and multiplayer Apps using Sockets and RTC. for very interesting projects.

Tech used IONIC / JAVASCRIPT / FIREBASE / NODE Js / VueJS / React / GraphQL / ANGULAR / MongoDB / WebRTC / Socket.IO PHP (Laravel / Zend) And CMS's (WordPress) / Cake / Unitv3D / Android Studio / IOS - XCode.

BACK-END / FRONT-END DEVELOPER - eltiempo.com· Colombia

03.2013 - 04.2018.

Hierarchy: Senior / Semi-senior · Sector: Programming · Industry: Media.

EL TIEMPO is the main newspaper in Colombia.

I was backend and frontend developer for their website that is the principal newspaper from Colombia with more than 10 million visits per day.

Everyday we had to make improvements in both, as data as infrastructure, so I can work as backend as the frontend also.

Tech used PHP / JAVASCRIPT / PostgreSQL / MySqI / SQL SERVER/ ZEND FRAMEWORK / JQuery, Bootstrap, CSS.

Backend/Frontend Web Developer MTV Networks Latin America · Argentina

02.2009 - 12.2012

Hierarchy: Senior / Semi-Senior · Sector: Programming · Industry: Other

My mainly task at MTV was to develop for all the websites of VIACOM NETWORKS Latin America, some like: MTV, VH1, COMEDY CENTRAL and NICKELODEON (among others)

Tech used PHP / JAVASCRIPT / MYSQL / WORDPRESS / JAVA / GROOVY

Web Programming Teacher ImageCampus · Argentina

10.2009 - 12.2010

Hierarchy: Senior / Semi-Senior · Sector: Programming · Industry: Information &

Research Teacher.

Widgets Developer Animacol · Colombia

01.2006 - 02.2009

Hierarchy: Senior / Semi-Senior · Sector: Engineering Technical Office / Project ·

Industry: Internet

Before the boom of the Apps, they were called Widgets.

My main job was to develop applications (Widgets) for CNN and its affiliates.

Web Developer Panamalive · Panamá

11.2000 - 12.2005

Hierarchy: Head / Coordinator / Supervisor · Sector: Engineering Technical Office /

Project · Industry: Internet

In that company, my job was to develop a website where the people can schedule the most importants events in Panama (2000-2005).

I have worked as a freelance for many years as well.

Developed many applications like **fitpal.co** (lonic + Php - PostgreSQL, one of the best startups at 2018 in Colombia)

Also a whole system of E-learning (https://e-learning.clinicarenovar.com) with Angular + Material / Firebase.

Among many other applications.

For several years I have worked in both Back End and Front End.

SKILLS /

- JavaScript.
- JQUERY
- Bootstrap.
- HTML/HTML5 / CSS/XHTML
- AngularJS Angular / IONIC
- Node.JS /
- React JS / Native
- PHP
- VueJS
- MySql.
- SQL-Server.
- Oracle.
- PostgreSQL.
- Firebase.
- NoSQL (MongoDB, CouchDB)
- GraphQL
- PHP
- Zend.
- Symfony.
- Laravel.
- Cake PHP
- CMS (Wordpress)
- Unity Test
- CodeSniffer.
- Maven.
- JBehaves.
- qUnit.
- PhpUnit
- JSlint
- Facebook API.
- ANDROID STUDIO.
- XCODE.
- CORDOVA.
- Nginx
- Apache
- AWS.
- Firebase Console.

jufrapps.co